ccbchurch.com 2019-05-29

# Privacy Policy - Church Community Builder

This Application collects some Personal Data from its Users.

* * *

## Data Controller and Owner

Church Community Builder/10807 New Allegiance Drive, Suite 300 Colorado Springs, CO 80921,  
privacy@churchcommunitybuilder.com

* * *

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookie, Usage data and Email address.

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection.  
The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application.  
Any use of Cookies - or of other tracking tools - by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.  
Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services.

Users are responsible for any Personal Data of third parties obtained, published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

* * *

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

* * *

## The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Infrastructure monitoring, Heat mapping, Analytics, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, SPAM protection, Hosting and backend infrastructure, Advertising, Traffic optimization and distribution, Managing support and contact requests, Content performance and features testing (A/B testing), Managing contacts and sending messages, Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting and Displaying content from external platforms.

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

* * *

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

> ### Advertising
> 
> These services allow User Data to be utilized for advertising communication purposes displayed in the form of banners and other advertisements on this Application, possibly based on User interests.  
> This does not mean that all Personal Data are used for this purpose. Information and conditions of use are shown below.  
> Some of the services listed below may use Cookies to identify Users or they may use the behavioral retargeting technique, i.e. displaying ads tailored to the User’s interests and behavior, including those detected outside this Application. For more information, please check the privacy policies of the relevant services.
> 
> #### BING ADS (MICROSOFT CORPORATION)
> 
> Bing Ads is an advertising service provided by Microsoft Corporation.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.microsoft.com/privacystatement/en-us/MicrosoftOnlineAdvertising/Default.aspx) –[](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=286759)

> ### Analytics
> 
> The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.
> 
> #### HUBSPOT
> 
> HubSpot Inc. is a third party company utilized for markteting automation and analytics services.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy?__hstc=162943075.5b2ba5d1290e76fa26836dce257bec17.1582080434242.1582080434242.1582080434242.1&__hssc=162943075.1.1582080434243&__hsfp=3924935683)
> 
> #### GOOGLE ANALYTICS (GOOGLE INC.)
> 
> Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
> Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)
> 
> #### GOOGLE TAG MANAGER (GOOGLE)
> 
> Google Tag Manager is an analytics service provided by Google, Inc.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)
> 
> #### GOOGLE ADWORDS CONVERSION TRACKING (GOOGLE INC.)
> 
> Google AdWords conversion tracking is an analytics service provided by Google Inc. that connects data from the Google AdWords advertising network with actions performed on this Application.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)
> 
> #### GOOGLE ANALYTICS DEMOGRAPHICS AND INTEREST REPORTING (GOOGLE INC.)
> 
> Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”), which enables Google Analytics to collect data about our site traffic via Google advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers to help us identify understand our Users according to their Age, Gender, and Interests.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Google Advertising Cookies and Anonymous Identifiers.
> 
> Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – Google Ads Settings – Opt Out
> 
> #### Flurry (Yahoo, Inc)
> 
> The Flurry Analytics Software Developer Kit provides tools and resources to gain a deep level of understanding of users’ behavior in mobile apps, enhancing app performance through tracking and advanced analysis of complex events, with metrics, segments, and funnels.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage Data
> 
> Place of Processing: USA - [Privacy Policy](https://developer.yahoo.com/flurry/legal-privacy/tos.html)
> 
> #### WORDPRESS STATS (AUTOMATTIC INC.)
> 
> Wordpress Stats is an analytics service provided by Automattic Inc.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://automattic.com/privacy/)
> 
> #### Fabric (Crashlytics)
> 
> Provides in-progress crash reporting to reduce the time between detecting, accessing, and fixing software issues much shorter, optimizing the app stability and providing an always-on picture of the health of mobile apps.
> 
> Personal data collected: Cookie and Usage Data
> 
> Place of Processing: USA - Privacy Policy

> ### Content performance and features testing (A/B testing)
> 
> The services contained in this section allow the Owner to track and analyze the User response concerning web traffic or behavior regarding changes to the structure, text or any other component of this Application.
> 
> #### GOOGLE WEBSITE OPTIMIZER (GOOGLE)
> 
> Google Website Optimizer is an A/B testing service provided by Google Inc.  
> Google may use Personal Data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)
> 
> #### HUBSPOT
> 
> HubSpot Inc. is a third party company utilized for markteting automation and analytics services.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy?__hstc=162943075.5b2ba5d1290e76fa26836dce257bec17.1582080434242.1582080434242.1582080434242.1&__hssc=162943075.1.1582080434243&__hsfp=3924935683)

> ### Displaying content from external platforms
> 
> These services allow you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them.  
> If a service of this kind is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when users do not use it.
> 
> #### VIMEO VIDEO (VIMEO, LLC)
> 
> Vimeo is a video content visualization service provided by Vimeo, LLC that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://vimeo.com/privacy)
> 
> #### WISTIA WIDGET (WISTIA, INC.)
> 
> Wistia is a video content visualization service provided by Wistia, Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://wistia.com/privacy)

> ### Heat mapping
> 
> Heat Mapping services are used to display the areas of a page where Users most frequently move the mouse or click. This shows where the points of interest are. These services make it possible to monitor and analyze web traffic and keep track of User behavior.
> 
> #### SESSIONCAM (SERVICETICK LIMITED)
> 
> SessionCam is a heat mapping service provided by ServiceTick Limited.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: UK – [Privacy Policy](http://www.sessioncam.com/privacy-policy-cookies/)
> 
> #### CRAZYEGG (CRAZYEGG)
> 
> Crazyegg is a heat mapping service provided by Crazy Egg Inc.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.crazyegg.com/privacy)

> ### Hosting and backend infrastructure
> 
> These services have the purpose of hosting data and files that enable this Application to run and be distributed as well as to provide a ready-made infrastructure to run specific features or parts of this Application. Some of these services work through geographically distributed servers, making it difficult to determine the actual location where the Personal Data are stored.
> 
> #### HUBSPOT
> 
> HubSpot Inc. is a third party company utilized for markteting automation and hosting services.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy?__hstc=162943075.5b2ba5d1290e76fa26836dce257bec17.1582080434242.1582080434242.1582080434242.1&__hssc=162943075.1.1582080434243&__hsfp=3924935683)

> ### Infrastructure monitoring
> 
> These services allow this Application to monitor the use and behavior of its components so its performance, operation, maintenance and troubleshooting can be improved.  
> Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and mode of implementation of these services, whose function is to filter the activities of this Application.
> 
> #### PINGDOM (PINGDOM AB)
> 
> Pingdom is a monitoring service provided by Pingdom AB.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: Sweden – [Privacy Policy](https://www.pingdom.com/legal/privacy-policy/)

> ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms
> 
> These services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Application.  
> The interaction and information obtained by this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
> If a service enabling interaction with social networks is installed it may still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.
> 
> #### ADDTHIS (ADDTHIS INC.)
> 
> AddThis is a service provided by Clearspring Technologies Inc., which displays a widget that allows interaction with social networks and external platforms as well as sharing the contents of this Application.  
> Depending on the configuration, this service can display widgets belonging to third parties such as the managers of social networks where interactions are shared. In this case, also the third parties that provide the widget will be informed of interactions and Usage Data on the pages where this service is installed.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy)
> 
> #### TWITTER TWEET BUTTON AND SOCIAL WIDGETS (TWITTER)
> 
> The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter Inc.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://twitter.com/privacy)

> ### Managing contacts and sending messages
> 
> These services make it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.  
> These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.
> 
> #### HUBSPOT
> 
> HubSpot Inc. is a third party company utilized for markteting automation and emailing services.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://legal.hubspot.com/privacy-policy?__hstc=162943075.5b2ba5d1290e76fa26836dce257bec17.1582080434242.1582080434242.1582080434242.1&__hssc=162943075.1.1582080434243&__hsfp=3924935683)

> ### Managing support and contact requests
> 
> These services allow this Application to manage support and contact requests received via email or by other means, such as the contact form.  
> The Personal Data processed depend on the information provided by the User in the messages and the means used for communication (e.g. email address).
> 
> #### DESK.COM (SALESFORCE.COM, INC.)
> 
> Desk.com is a support and contact request management service provided by salesforce.com, inc.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.desk.com/privacy)

> ### Remarketing and Behavioral Targeting
> 
> These services allow this Application and its partners to inform, optimize and serve advertising based on past use of this Application by the User.  
> This activity is performed by tracking Usage Data and by using Cookies, information that is transferred to the partners that manage the remarketing and behavioral targeting activity.
> 
> #### PERFECT AUDIENCE (NOWSPOTS, INC.)
> 
> Perfect Audience is an advertising service provided by NowSpots, Inc.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.perfectaudience.com/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://www.perfectaudience.com/privacy/index.html#opt-out)

> ### SPAM protection
> 
> These services analyze the traffic of this Application, potentially containing Users' Personal Data, with the purpose of filtering it from parts of traffic, messages and content that are recognized as SPAM.
> 
> #### AKISMET (AUTOMATTIC INC.)
> 
> Akismet is a SPAM protection service provided by Automattic Inc.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://automattic.com/privacy/)

> ### Traffic optimization and distribution
> 
> These services allow this Application to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.  
> Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between this Application and the User's browser.  
> Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information User are transferred.
> 
> #### CLOUDFLARE (CLOUDFLARE)
> 
> CloudFlare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by CloudFlare Inc.  
> The way CloudFlare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through this Application, i.e., communication between this Application and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data from this Application to be collected.
> 
> Personal Data collected: Cookie and Various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service.
> 
> Place of processing: USA – [Privacy Policy](http://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy)

* * *

## Further information about Personal Data

> ### The Service is not directed to children under the age of 13
> 
> This Application is not directed to children under the age of 13. It doesn't require the child to disclose any more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in its activity.  
> Parents may review the personal information about their child collected by this Application - if any - outlined in the rest of this policy, ask for its deletion and request any further collection or use to be omitted by contacting the Owner. Parents may also agree to the collection and use of their child’s information, but still not allow disclosure to third parties, unless disclosure is integral to the Service.

* * *

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

### Specific data search methodologies to facilitate quick and accurate application user login

Church Community Builder may employ specific data search methodologies to facilitate quick and accurate application user login for the benefit of churches, organizations, customers, and users. Specifically, these data searches are designed to direct users to the correct database for application login and may include, but are not limited to, user searches for the correct church, organization, or customer database utilizing search parameters of church, organization, or customer name; church, organization, or customer location; or user specific identification, such as an individual user's name. These searches may disclose a church, organization, or customer as having a contractual relationship with Church Community Builder, as well as disclosing the fact of a specific individual, by name, as having a potential relationship as a user with one or more church, organization, or customer of Church Community Builder.

### System Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

### The rights of Users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above.

This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies.

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller removes the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.

### Information about this privacy policy

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on Iubenda's servers.

* * *
